ILGWU (digital) 5780 (d)
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU (digital)
1989-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780 (d)
0.25 cubic feet
0.2 linear ft.
Computer floppy disks.
This collection consists of digital records from the ILGWU.
16203072
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, April 07, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, April 07, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
16203072
- Modified Upgrade with "Reformed By" fields, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- NB (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Nathalie Gomez Documents from the Internet (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Files (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  ID/LM; IoR; ID/LM (old); PP; Subject; Unite; Distrib. Mat.
- Old Word Perfect 5.0 files (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Maureen Wiggan's period
- No Label (Box 1, Folder 6)
- No Label (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Intake forms; Birth Trans form; Registry Letter form (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Records; Receipt Books (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Formatted Certiform (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Student Backup: Immigration (Box 1, Folder 11)
- DB (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Fast Back Full Backup: Disk 1, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  December 4, 1989
- Fast Back Full Backup: Disk 2, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Fast Back Full Backup: Disk 3, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Fast Back Full Backup: Disk 4, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Work Disk (Box 1, Folder 17)
- April, May, June Tangram Docs (Box 1, Folder 18)
- All WP Files (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Copy of MM3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  .Doc and Dok
- Copy MM2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Claudette (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Copy of MM1 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Drive A: Hafeez 5.0 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Legislation Paper (Box 1, Folder 25)
- IMA Amnesty (Box 1, Folder 26)
- AN, AT, JR, NL, MZ, MW, FO (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Word Perfect Files
- 1 file: /mm/wp.exe (Box 1, Folder 28)
- FIS (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Formatted: Vijay Chawla, Figueroa-Galinto (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Immigration Project Files: Director M. C. Files, J. R. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Formatted: mm Training (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Drive B.
- Nancy Forms and Letters. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Drive A. Copy \wp\im*.*
- PB\Immigrat (Box 1, Folder 34)
- No Label (Box 1, Folder 35)
- No Label (Box 1, Folder 36)
- No Label (Box 1, Folder 37)
- No Label (Box 1, Folder 38)